身材矮小的野蛮拾荒者
你又犯了一个错误 索洛 你就是想赖账
两次
你也无处可躲
- 搜查这艘运输舰 - 明白
发现抵抗者
你们要找的机器人也在这
通知第一秩序 我找到机器人了
很久很久以前 在一个遥远的银河系....
卢克・天行者不知所踪
在他消失数年中
邪恶的第一秩序...
从帝国的灰烬中悄然崛起
在除掉最后一个绝地武士 天行者之前
第一秩序绝不卸甲休兵
在共和国的鼎力支持下
莱娅・奥加纳将军
领导着一个勇敢的抵抗组织
她急需想要找到哥哥卢克
从而在他的帮助下
恢复银河系的和平与正义
莱娅已派出最英勇的飞行员
前往贾库星球执行秘密任务
一位昔日的盟友在那里发现了
有关卢克下落的重要线索....
这个东西会让一切步入正轨的
This will begin to make things right.
我已游历各处 阅尽沧桑
I've traveled too far and seen too much
以致忽略了弥漫在银河系中的绝望
to ignore the despair in the galaxy.
没有了绝地 原力绝无平衡的可能
Without the Jedi, there can be no balance in the Force.
正是因为你 如今我们才拥有了一个机会
Well, because of you, now we have a chance.
将军已经追查此事许久了
The General's been after this for a long time.
将军
Oh, the General?
对我来说她可是皇室
To me, she is royalty.
她当然是了
Well, she certainly is that.
有人来了
We got company.
你得藏起来
You have to hide.
你得离开
You have to leave.
快走
Go.
全体出发 冲啊
Get out! Go! Go! Go!
快来 BB-8 动作快点
Come on, BB-8, hurry!
炸掉那架X翼战机
Blast that X-wing!
开火 后方有敌人来了
Over there! Over there!
我看到了
I see them.
你帮我拿着
You take this.
它在你身上会更安全
It's safer with you than it is with me.
赶快离开这里 越远越好
You get as far away from here as you can.
- 听明白了吗 - 我不知道...
Do you hear me?
我会回来找你的
I'll come back for you.
我们都会没事的
It will be all right.
继续前进
Keep moving!
守在这里
Stay here.
瞧瞧你都老成什么样了
Look how old you've become.
而你经历了比变老糟糕得多的事情
Something far worse has happened to you.
你明白我为何而来
You know what I've come for.
我知道你从何而来
I know where you come from.
在你称呼自己为凯洛・伦之前
Before you called yourself Kylo Ren.
天行者所在位置的地图
The map to Skywalker.
我们知道在你身上
We know you found it.
现在你要将这份地图上交给第一秩序
And now you're going to give it to the First Order.
第一秩序源自于黑暗面
The First Order rose from the dark side.
而你不是
You did not.
我会让你见识一下黑暗面的
I'll show you the dark side.
尽管来
You may try.
但你不可否认的事实是 那是你的家人
But you cannot deny the truth that is your family.
你说的太对了
You're so right.
那么 是谁先开始讲话呢 你还是我
So, who talks first? You talk first? I talk first?
老家伙把地图交给你了
The old man gave it to you.
戴着那东西 我很难听懂你说话...
It's just very hard to understand you with all the...
- 给我搜 - 我...
- Search him. - ...apparatus.
- 什么也没有 长官 - 把他带到船上
- Nothing, sir. - Put him on board.
长官 村民如何处置
Sir, the villagers?
全部灭口
Kill them all.
听我命令
On my command.
开火
Fire.
不要啊
Please, no!
这里什么也没有 清除这架战机
Nothing here. Go ahead!
行了
All right.
我自己走
All right!
FN-2187
FN-2187.
上交你的爆能枪以供检查
Submit your blaster for inspection.
遵命 队长
Yes, Captain.
谁准许你摘掉头盔的
And who gave you permission to remove that helmet?
是我的错 队长
I'm sorry, Captain.
马上去我的部门报告
Report to my division at once.
今天你带过来的东西也就值...
What you brought me today is worth...
嗯
hmm...
四分之一份口粮
one quarter portion.
太感谢啦
Oh, thank you.
嘘
Shh.
那是个蒂多 想把你拆成零件
That's just Teedo. Wants you for parts.
他对任何人都没有丝毫的尊重
He has no respect for anyone.
你的天线折弯了
Your antenna's bent.
你来自哪里
Where do you come from?
我不能讲的 这是机密
I am not suppose to tell, it's classified.
机密 真的假的
Classified, really?
我也是机密人士
Me too. Big secret.
尼伊马贸易哨站在那个方向 离开尔文山脉远一点
Niima Outpost is that way. Stay off Kelvin Ridge.
千万别靠近北部下沉区
Keep away from the Sinking Fields in the north.
否则你会淹没在沙子里的
You'll drown in the sand.
你真是太善良啦 我想跟你一起走
You are so very kind. I would like to come with you.
别跟着我 镇子在那个方向
Don't follow me. Town is that way.
那我可以跟你待在一起吗
Oh. Then, can I stay with you?
不行
No!
人家好害怕的
I am scared.
明早你就出发离开
In the morning, you go.
再次谢谢你
Thank you, again.
不客气
You're welcome.
我们抓到了抵抗组织的王牌飞行员
I had no idea we had the best pilot
我竟毫不知情
in the Resistance on board.
躺得还舒服吗
Comfortable?
不太舒服
Not really.
我很是佩服
I'm impressed.
居然没人能撬开你的嘴 获取地图的下落
No one has been able to get out of you what you did with the map.
你可得重新考虑下你的审问技巧了
You might want to rethink your technique.
地图在哪里
Where is it?
抵抗组织不会屈服于你的淫威之下的
The Resistance... will not be intimidated by you.
到底在哪里
Where... is it?
地图藏在一个BB型机器人体内
It's in a droid. A BB unit.
好 如果这个机器人在贾库 我们很快就会找到它的
Well, then, if it's on Jakku, we'll soon have it.
那这件事就交给你了
I leave that to you.
不要放弃希望 他还是可能会出现的
Don't give up hope. He still might show up.
不管你等的是谁
Whoever it is you're waiting for.
机密人物
Classified.
我十分了解等待的滋味
I know all about waiting.
我的家人
For my family.
总有一天会回来的
They'll be back. One day.
来吧
Come on.
这五件价值...
These five pieces are worth...
让我想想
Let me see here... hmm...
二分之一份口粮
one half portion.
上周每一件还值二分之一口粮的
Last week they were a half portion each.
这个机器人呢
What about the droid?
机器人怎么了
What about him?
我愿意买下他
I'll pay for him.
60份口粮
Sixty portions.
其实
Actually...
这个机器人我不卖
The droid's not for sale.
走吧
Come on.
跟着这个女孩 给我抓到那个机器人
Follow the girl and get that droid.
伦要见犯人
Ren wants the prisoner.
这边转弯
Turn here.
好好听着
Listen carefully.
如果你完全按照我说的做 我可以帮你离开这里
If you do exactly as I say, I can get you out of here.
你说啥
What?
这是一项援救行动 我是来帮你逃出去的
This is a rescue. I'm helping you escape.
你会驾驶TIE战斗机吗
Can you fly a TIE fighter?
你是抵抗组织成员吗
You're with the Resistance?
什么 不是 我只是来帮你逃出去
What? No, no, no. I'm breaking you out.
你会驾驶TIE战斗机吗
- Can you fly a TIE fighter?
没有什么飞行器是我驾驶不了的
- I can fly anything.
为什么 你为什么帮我
Why? Why are you helping me?
因为这才是应该做的事情
Because it's the right thing to do.
你需要一位飞行员
You need a pilot.
我的确需要一位飞行员
I need a pilot.
我们就要逃出去了
We're gonna do this.
是吗
Yeah?
好了 保持冷静
Okay. Stay calm. Stay calm.
- 我挺冷静的 - 我是在跟自己说
- I am calm. - I'm talking to myself.
还不行
Not yet.
可以了 这边走
Okay, go. This way.
我一直都想着能驾驶一下TIE战斗机呢
I've always wanted to fly one of these things.
- 你会射击吗 - 我会用爆能枪
- Can you shoot? - Blasters, I can.
好 原理是一样的
Okay, same principle.
使用左侧开关切换导弹 加农炮和麦加脉冲
Use the toggle on the left to switch between missiles, cannons and mag pulse.
右边的准星用来瞄准
Use the sight on the right to aim.
- 扳柄用来开火 - 这也太复杂了吧
- Triggers to fire. - This is very complicated.
我能解决
I can fix this.
第二停机场有一架战机未经许可起飞
We have an unsanctioned departure from bay two.
通知赫克斯将军 并阻止那艘战机
Alert General Hux. And stop that fighter.
- 十四失败 十八 - 搞定
- Fourteen failed. Eighteen... - I got it.
这家伙速度真快
This thing really moves.
好了 我们要是想跑远点
We gotta take out as many of these cannons as we can...
就得尽可能地炸掉这些加农炮
or we're not gonna get very far.
- 好的 - 我会驾驶到适当位置
- All right. - I'm gonna get us in position.
保持警惕
Just stay sharp.
前方 前方 看到了吗
Up ahead! Up ahead! You see it?
我驾驶到正中央了
I got us dead center.
- 这一发畅通无阻 - 明白
- It's a clean shot. - Okay, got it.
- 太棒了 - 真厉害
- Yeah! - Yes!
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
- 看到有多准了吗 - 看到了
- Did you see that? - I saw it!
嘿 你叫什么
Hey, what's your name?
FN-2187
FN-2187.
F...什么来着
F... What?
这是他们给我的唯一名字
That's the only name they ever gave me.
我不会用这个来称呼你 FN 是吧
Well, I ain't using it. F-N, huh?
芬恩 我打算叫你芬恩
Finn. I'm gonna call you Finn.
- 可以吗 - 芬恩
- Is that all right? - Finn.
好 芬恩 我喜欢这个名字
Yeah. Finn, I like that.
- 我太喜欢啦 - 我是波 波・达默龙
- I like that. - I'm Poe. Poe Dameron.
- 很高兴认识你 波 - 我也是
- Good to meet you, Poe. - Good to meet you too, Finn.
长官 那两个家伙把我们的涡轮激光炮炸毁了
Sir, they've taken out our turbolasers.
使用腹侧炮
Use the ventral cannons.
遵命 长官 正在激活腹侧炮
Yes, sir. Bringing them online.
赫克斯将军 是那个抵抗组织的飞行员吗
General Hux, is it the Resistance pilot?
是的 而帮他逃出去的是我们自己人中的一个
Yes, and he had help from one of our own.
正在检查登记信息以识别出该冲锋兵的身份
We're checking the registers now to identify which stormtrooper it was.
是来自村庄那个 FN-2187
The one from the village. FN-2187.
长官 腹侧炮准备完毕
Sir, ventral cannons hot.
发射
Fire.
朝着你过来的是什么 在我右边 你的左边
One's coming toward you! My right. Your left.
- 看到了吗 - 等等
- Do you see it? - Hold on.
我看到了
I see him!
干得漂亮
Nice shot!
我们这是往哪里去
Where are we going?
我们得返回贾库
We're going back to Jakku. That's where.
不不不 我们不能回去
No. We can't go back to Jakku.
我们得赶紧逃出这个星系
We need to get out of this system.
我必须抢在第一秩序之前找到我的机器人
I gotta get my droid before the First Order does.
- 什么 机器人 - 没错
- What, a droid? - That's right.
BB型机器人 橙白相间 独一无二
He's a BB unit, orange and white. One of a kind.
我才不在乎他是什么颜色
I don't care what color he is!
一个机器人不重要
No droid can be that important.
这个机器人举足轻重 兄弟
This one is, pal!
我们需要离第一秩序远一点 越远越好
We gotta get as far away from the First Order as we can.
回到贾库 必死无疑
We go back to Jakku, we die.
这个机器人携带着一个能指引我们
That droid has a map that leads
找到卢克・天行者的地图
straight to Luke Skywalker.
你在逗我吧
Oh, you gotta be kidding me!
FN-2187向我的部门报告
FN-2187 reported to my division...
进行评估之后 送去重建条件反射
was evaluated, and sent to reconditioning.
之前没有失控的征兆吗
No prior signs of nonconformity?
这是他第一次进攻
This was his first offense.
将军
General!
- 他们被击中了 - 剿灭了吗
- They've been hit. - Destroyed?
已丧失战斗力
Disabled.
他们往贾库去了
They were headed back to Jakku.
CIS推断坠机发生在戈亚逊石漠
The fighter is projected to crash in the Goazon badlands.
他们回去找机器人了
They were going back for the droid.
派出小队去往残骸处
Send a squad to the wreckage.
波
Poe!
波 我来救你
Poe! I got you.
波
Poe!
最高领袖斯诺克的命令很明确
Supreme Leader Snoke was explicit.
尽可能活捉机器人 如果情况紧急 就摧毁它
Capture the droid if we can, but destroy it if we must.
将军 你的士兵有多少能耐呢
How capable are your soldiers, General?
我不会让你质疑我的方法的
I won't have you question my methods.
他们在犯叛国罪方面显然训练有素
They're obviously skilled at committing high treason.
或许斯诺克领袖应该考虑下使用克隆人军队
Perhaps Leader Snoke should consider using a clone army.
我的士兵都是经过特殊训练的
My men are exceptionally trained.
自出生起就按照预定步骤进行
Programmed from birth.
那么他们就完全可以找回机器人
Then they should have no problem retrieving the droid.
并且是毫发无损
Unharmed.
小心点 伦 你的个人兴趣
Careful, Ren, that your personal interests...
妨碍了领袖斯诺克命令的执行
not interfere with orders from Leader Snoke.
我想要那张地图
I want that map.
为你着想
For your sake...
我建议你还是想办法找到它吧
I suggest you get it.
水 水啊
Water. Water.
没水
No water.
- 有水吗 - 没有
Water.
还有水吗
Is there water?
姑娘 你的机器人 我想要
Girl, your droid. I want it.
什么 离他远点
What? Oi, get off him!
嘿
Hey!
那些家伙是什么人哪
Who are those people.
他们为昂卡工作
They work for Unkar.
那些家伙想要你
That guy that wanted you.
他肯定真的很想要你
He must have really wanted you.
小姐 那个男人
Mistress! That man!
谁
Who?
那边那个
That man over there.
就是他
Him?
是的
Yes.
他穿着我主人的外套
He is wearing my master's jacket.
- 小贼 你急什么呢 - 啥 小贼
- What's your hurry, thief? - What? Thief?
噢
Ow!
- 嘿 你干嘛 - 这件外套
- Hey, what? - The jacket.
机器人说是你偷来的
This droid says you stole it.
我今天已经过得够糟糕了好不好
I've had a pretty messed up day, all right?
要是你不再指控我 我会十分感谢
So I'd appreciate it if you stop accusing me of...
- 别这么干了 - 你从哪搞来的
- Ow! Stop it! - Where'd you get it?
这是它主人的东西
It belongs to his master.
波・达默龙的外套 这是他的名字 对不对
It belonged to Poe Dameron. That was his name, right?
他被第一秩序俘虏了
He was captured by the First Order.
我帮他逃了出来 然后我们的飞船坠毁了
I helped him escape, but our ship crashed.
波没能挺过来
Poe didn't make it.
我尝试去救他 但没成功
I tried to help him. I'm sorry.
所以你是抵抗组织的人
So you're with the Resistance?
显而易见
Obviously.
没错
Yes, I am.
我是抵抗组织的人 对
I'm with the Resistance, yeah.
我是抵抗组织的一员
I am with the Resistance.
我之前从没见过抵抗组织的战士
I've never met a Resistance fighter before.
就长我这样 我们的一部分人长这样
Well, this is what we look like.
其他人长别的样子
Some of us. Others look different.
BB-8说他在执行一个秘密任务
BB-8 says he's on a secret mission.
他必须返回你们的基地
He has to get back to your base.
据说他有一份通向卢克・天行者所在地的地图
Apparently, he has a map that leads to Luke Skywalker
所有人都想得到它
and everyone's after it.
卢克・天行者
Luke Skywalker?
我以为他是个神话
I thought he was a myth.
什么
What?
- 你在干什么 - 快跑
- What are you doing? - Come on.
跟上 BB-8
Come on, BB-8!
- 放开我 - 快跑 我们得离开这儿
- Let go of me! - Come on, we gotta move!
你不拉着我的手 我也知道怎么跑
I know how to run without you holding my hand!
BB-8 跟紧点
BB-8, stay close!
往这走
This way.
请求空中支援
Call in the air strike.
快点
Come on!
咱们俩都是他们的目标
They're shooting at both of us.
他们看见你跟我在一起 你已经被标记了
Yeah. They saw you with me. You're marked.
- 那还不是拜你所赐 - 嘿
- Well, thanks for that. - Hey!
直接用棍子把人抡倒可不是我
I'm not the one who chased you down with a stick.
这儿的人就没有爆能枪吗
Does anyone have blasters around here?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
别抓我的手
Stop taking my hand!
醒醒
Hey.
你没事吗
Are you okay?
恩
Yeah.
跟我来
Follow me.
- 我们跑不过他们 - 可以的 用那辆四跃飞船
- We can't outrun them! - We might in that quadjumper!
嗨 我们需要一个飞行员
Hey, we need a pilot!
已经有了
We've got one.
你吗
You?
那艘飞船怎么样
Uh, what about that ship?
那艘是垃圾
That one's garbage!
死马当活马医吧
The garbage will do.
射击手的位置在那下面
Gunner position is down there!
你驾驶过这飞船吗
You ever fly this thing?
没有 这飞船已经很多年没被使用过了
No! This ship hasn't flown in years.
好吧
Great.
哇哦
Whoa.
我能行的 我能做到
I can do this. I can do this.
嘿
Hey!
那是我的
That's mine!
等等 保持低空飞行 低空飞行
Wait, stay low! Hey, stay low!
- 什么 - 贴地飞行
- What? - Stay low!
扰乱他们的追踪
It confuses their tracking.
- BB-8 坐稳了 - 为森么
BB-8, hold on!
我要往下冲了
I'm going low!
你在后头干什么呢
What are you doing back there?
你还不还击 你在等什么
Are you ever gonna fire back?
我在想办法 保护罩打开了吗
I'm working on it! Are the shields up?
没有副驾驶员协助 我没那么轻松
Not so easy without a co-pilot!
那你应该试试坐在这玩意儿上
Try sitting in this thing.
我们需要掩护 立刻马上
We need cover, quick!
马上就会有了
We're about to get some!
希望如愿
I hope.
哇哦
Whoa.
该死的
Damn it!
拜托 给点力
Come on, come on!
- 干得好 - 我现在做射击手还挺厉害
- Nice shot! - I'm getting pretty good at this.
大家快趴下
Let's get down!
机关炮在冲前的位置上卡死了
Uh, the cannon's stuck in forward position.
我无法移动它 你只有甩掉他们才行了
I can't move it. You gotta lose him!
- 做好准备 - 好的 做什么准备
- Get ready! - Okay. For what?
我们真要这么做吗
Are we really doing this?
噢 不
Oh, no.
哇哦
Whoo!
- 刚才的飞行真厉害 - 你射击也不错
- Nice shooting. - Now that was some flying.
- 谢谢 - 你是怎么做到的
- Thanks. - How did you do that?
- 我也不知道 - 没人训练过你吗
- I don't know. - No one trained you?
但我还从来没飞离过星球
I've flown some ships, but I've never left the planet.
- 你的最后一击太棒了 - 那简直无与伦比
- Your last shot was dead-on. - That was amazing.
- 你爆掉了他 - 多亏了你的好助攻
- You got him with one blast! - You set me up for it.
- 简直是完美 - 确实很不错
- It was perfect. - That was pretty good.
你很安全 他是抵抗组织的一员
You're okay. He's with the Resistance.
他会带你回家的
He's gonna get you home.
我们一起
We both will.
我还不知道你的名字
I don't know your name.
芬恩 你叫什么
Finn. What's yours?
我是蕾伊
I'm Rey.
蕾伊
Rey...
来帮我处理这个 快点
Help me with this. Quick!
发生什么了
Whoa, what's going on?
长官 我们没能在贾库星抓捕到那个机器人
Sir... we were unable to acquire the droid on Jakku.
他乘坐一艘被盗的科瑞利安YT型号运输舰逃脱了追捕
It escaped capture aboard a stolen Corellian YT model freighter.
那个机器人
The droid...
偷走了一艘运输舰
stole a freighter?
并非如此 长官
Not exactly, sir.
他有帮手
It had help.
虽然还未经证实
We have no confirmation
但我们怀疑是FN-2187协助了他逃离
but we believe FN-2187 may have helped in the escape.
还有别的情况吗
Anything else?
与他们同行的还有一个女孩
The two were accompanied by a girl.
什么女孩
What girl?
是动力源的问题
It's the motivator.
给我一把哈里斯扳手 在那找找
Grab me a Harris wrench, check in there.
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
如果我们还想靠它活下去的话 不太好
If we wanna live, not good.
他们现在还在追捕我们
They're hunting for us now.
我们必须得离开这个星系
We've gotta get out of this system!
BB-8说抵抗组织基地的位置只有内部人员知道
BB-8 said the location of the Resistance base is "need to know".
如果我要带你们去那的话 我需要知道那个地点
If I'm taking you there, I need to know!
这个吗
This?
你得告诉我们你的基地在哪儿
You gotta tell us where your base is.
什么 不行
What? No.
我不会说你这门语言
I don't speak that.
好吧 我只告诉你
All right, between us...
我不是抵抗组织的人 好吧
I'm not with the Resistance, okay?
我只是想逃离第一秩序
I'm just trying to get away from the First Order.
不过如果你告诉我基地在哪儿
But you tell us where the base is...
我就把你先送到那去 成交吗
I'll get you there first. Deal?
- 机器人 拜托 - 派莱克斯扳手 快点
- Droid, please! - Pilex driver, hurry.
- 所以你们的基地在哪儿 - 好的 BB-8 告诉她
- So, where's your base? - Go on, BB-8, tell her.
咦 呃
Huh? Eh.
咦
Huh?
求你了
Please.
- 伊利尼姆星系 - 对 伊利尼姆星系
- The Ileenium system? - Yeah, the Ileenium system.
就是那 把我们送到那去 越快越好
That's the one. Get us there as fast as you can.
我把你们两个送到波尼马终点站
I'll drop you two at Ponemah Terminal.
我需要发动机胶带 赶紧
I need the bonding tape, hurry!
你要去哪儿
What about you?
我必须得回贾库星去
I gotta get back to Jakku.
回贾库
Back to Jak...
为什么所有人都要回贾库星
Why does everyone wanna go back to Jakku?
- 不是这个 不对 不对 - 那个地方
- It's not that one. No. No. - That place is...
是我手指的那个 不对
The one I'm pointing to. No.
不对 不对
No. No!
如果我们不把漏气的地方补上
If we don't patch it up...
毒气会从气箱里漫出来 有毒气体会充满整艘飞船
the propulsion tank will overflow and flood the ship with poisonous gas!
- 这个 - 是的
- This? - Yes.
嗨 蕾伊 你是一位飞行员
Hey, Rey, you're a pilot.
你想飞去哪儿都行 为什么要回去
You can fly anywhere. Why go back?
你有家人在那里
You got a family?
还是男朋友在那里 一个帅哥男友
You got a boyfriend? A cute boyfriend?
原因就是 关你屁事
None of your business, that's why.
- 准没什么好事 - 去驾驶舱
- That can't be good. - No, it can't be.
我们被人锁定了
Someone's locked on to us.
所有控制系统已经失灵
All controls are overridden.
放开 别碰我
Get off! Get off!
你看见什么了
See anything?
噢 不
Oh, no.
是第一秩序
It's the First Order.
我们要怎么办 肯定有什么对策
What do we do? There must be something.
- 你刚刚说有有毒气体 - 我已经堵上了
- You said poisonous gas. - I fixed that.
你能再把它打开吗
Can you unfix it?
过来 BB-8
Come on, BB-8.
我接住他了
I got him.
我没事
I'm okay.
BB-8 从我身上下来
BB-8, get off me!
你觉得这招对帝国冲锋队员有用吗
Do you think this will work on the stormtroopers?
有用 他们的面具可以过滤烟雾但不防毒
Yeah. Their masks filter out smoke, not toxins.
快点 他们来了
- Hurry. - I'm hurrying.
丘伊
Chewie...
我们回家了
we're home.
其他人在哪儿
Where are the others?
- 飞行员呢 - 我就是飞行员
- Where's the pilot? - I'm the pilot.
- 你 - 她在撒谎
You?
不 是真的 飞船上只有我们几个
No, it's true. We're the only ones on board.
你能听懂这玩意儿
You can understand that thing?
这玩意儿也能听得懂你说话 所以注意你的用词
And "that thing" can understand you, too, so watch it.
从那里面出来
Come on out of there.
- 你从哪里得到的这艘飞船 - 尼伊马贸易哨站
- Where'd you get this ship? - Niima Outpost.
贾库星 那个垃圾场
Jakku? That junkyard?
谢谢 就是个垃圾场
Thank you! Junkyard.
我跟你说过我们应该再搜索一遍西境
Told you we should have double-checked the Western Reaches.
它在谁手里 杜凯恩
Who had it? Ducain?
我偷了它 从昂卡・普拉特那
I stole it. From Unkar Plutt.
他从欧文兄弟那偷的 欧文兄弟是从杜凯恩那偷的
He stole it from the Irving Boys, who stole it from Ducain.
他偷的我的
Who stole it from me!
你告诉他汉・索洛
Well, you tell him that Han Solo...
如今又把千年隼偷回来了 不会再丢了
just stole back the Millennium Falcon for good.
这艘船是千年隼号 你就是汉・索洛
This is the Millennium Falcon? You're Han Solo?
我曾经是
I used to be.
汉・索洛 那个义军将军
Han Solo, the Rebellion general?
不 是走私犯
No, the smuggler.
他不是个战斗英雄吗
Wasn't he a war hero?
这就是那艘只用十四秒差距完成科舍尔航程的飞船
This is the ship that made the Kessel Run in 14 parsecs?
十二秒
Twelve!
什么十四秒
Fourteen.
嗨
Hey!
是哪个傻瓜在点火线上装了个压缩机
Some moof-milker put a compressor on the ignition line.
昂卡・普拉特做的
Unkar Plutt did.
我也觉得这是个错误 把太多压力留给了
I thought it was a mistake, too. Puts too much...
- 超光速推进器 - 超光速推进器
...stress on the hyperdrive.
丘伊 把他们扔到飞行舱里
Chewie, throw them in a pod.
我们一会儿把他们放到最近的无人星上
We'll drop them at the nearest inhabited planet.
等等 不行
Wait, no.
- 我们需要你的帮助 - 我的帮助
- We need your help. - My help?
这个机器人必须尽快赶到抵抗组织基地
This droid has to get to the Resistance base as soon as possible.
他携带着一份通向卢克・天行者所在地的地图
He's carrying a map to Luke Skywalker.
你是大名鼎鼎的汉・索洛 和义军并肩作战过
You are the Han Solo that fought with the Rebellion.
你肯定知道他
You knew him.
是的 我知道他
Yeah. I knew him.
我认识卢克
I knew Luke.
别告诉我有一只拉思塔逃跑了
Don't tell me a Rathtar's gotten loose.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
你刚刚是说了拉思塔吗
Did you just say Rathtars?
嗨
Hey!
你不是在用这艘运输舰走私拉思塔吧
You're not hauling Rathtars on this freighter, are you?
我就是在运送拉思塔
I'm hauling Rathtars.
瓜维亚死亡帮来了
Oh, great. It's the Guavian Death Gang.
他们一定是从南图区域就开始追踪我们
Must have tracked us from Nantoon.
拉思塔是什么
What's a Rathtar?
它们体型很大并且很危险
They're big and they're dangerous.
你听说过特里利亚大屠杀吗
You ever heard of the Trillia Massacre?
- 没有 - 挺好的
- No. - Good.
我要送三只到普拉纳王国去
I got three of them going to King Prana.
三只 你是怎么把它们弄上船的
Three? How'd you get them on board?
我们之前人手更多些
I used to have a bigger crew.
到下面去 我让你们上来再上来
Get below and stay there until I say so...
别打千年隼的主意
and don't even think about taking the Falcon.
BB-8怎么办
What about BB-8?
在我甩掉这帮人之前 他先跟着我
He stays with me until I get rid of the gang...
之后你们就可以带着他 爱去哪儿去哪儿了
then you can have him back and be on your way.
那拉思塔怎么办 你把它们放在哪儿了
What about the Rathtars? Where are you keeping them?
- 那有一只 - 你打算做什么
- There's one. - What are you gonna do?
老样子 按我的方式解决问题
Same thing I always do. Talk my way out of it.
你有成功过吗
Do you?
当然 次次管用
Yes, I do. Every time.
汉・索洛
Han Solo.
你死定了
You're a dead man.
巴拉-蒂克 有什么问题吗
Bala-Tik. What's the problem?
我们借了你50000块干这趟活儿 这就是问题
The problem is we loaned you 50,000 for this job.
- 你能看见他们吗 -看不见
- Can you see them? - No.
我听说你也向坎吉俱乐部借了50000块
I heard you also borrowed 50,000 from Kanjiklub.
你知道的 那些小怪物不可信
You know you can't trust those little freaks.
咱们都认识多久了
How long we known each other?
他们有爆能枪
They have blasters.
有很多
A lot of them.
时间不长 我们现在想要回那笔钱
Not long. We want our money back now.
你觉得捕捉拉思塔不要钱吗
You think hunting Rathtars is cheap?
那钱我已经花了
I spent that money.
坎吉俱乐部也想要回他们的资金
Kanjiklub wants their investment back, too.
我从没和坎吉俱乐部做过交易
I never made a deal with Kanjiklub!
这话你自己跟坎吉俱乐部说
Tell that to Kanjiklub.
塔苏・利奇
Tasu Leech.
很高兴见到你啊
Good to see you.
兄弟们 我答应好的东西我会给你们的
Boys, you're both gonna get what I promised.
难道我曾经有
Have I ever not delivered...
- 言而无信过吗 - 有啊
- for you before? - Yeah.
- 第二次是什么事 - 故技重施
- What was the second time? - Your game is old.
在这个星系里不会有人再相信你的骗局了
There's no one in the galaxy left for you to swindle.
那个BB型机器人
That BB unit.
第一秩序正在找的那个机器人 跟它一模一样
The First Order is looking for one just like it.
还有两个逃犯
And two fugitives.
这事我第一次听说
First I've heard of it.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
如果我们可以把走廊上的防爆门关上
If we close the blast doors in that corridor
就能把那两帮的人困住
we can trap both gangs!
从这里把门关上吗
We'll close the blast doors from here?
重新设定导火线应该就能行
Resetting the fuses should do it.
我有种不好的预感
I got a bad feeling about this.
- 惨了 - 什么惨了
- Oh, no. - "Oh, no," what?
拨错导火线了
Wrong fuses.
杀了他们
Kill them!
- 哦 - 抓住那个机器人
- Whoa... - And take the droid!
- 这是个错误的决定 - 错大发了
- This was a mistake! - Huge!
它们长什么样子
What do they look like?
就长那样
They look like that.
- 往这走 - 你确定吗
- This way. - Are you sure?
不 不 不 不
No, no, no!
芬恩
Finn!
蕾伊
Rey!
别碰我
Get off! Get off!
- 蕾伊 - 芬恩
- Rey! - Finn!
芬恩
Finn!
放开我
Get off me!
蕾伊
Rey!
滚开 滚开
Get off! Get off!
芬恩
Finn!
- 它抓住我了 但是那门 - 真是幸运
- It had me! But the door... - That was lucky.
我来开门 掩护我
I got the door. Cover us!
丘伊
Chewie!
还好吗
You okay?
还好
Yeah.
哇
Wow.
快 快
Come on! Come on!
汉
Han.
你 把门关上 你 照顾丘伊
You, close the door behind us. You, take care of Chewie!
啊
Awww!
你干嘛
Hey, where are you going?
昂卡・普拉特在这安装了一个燃油泵
Unkar Plutt installed a fuel pump, too.
不把它填装好 我们哪也去不了
If we don't prime that, we're not going anywhere.
我恨他
I hate that guy.
- 你以前还有副驾驶 - 有一个 现在在后面
- And you could use a co-pilot. - I got one, he's back there.
看着推进器 我们要以光速离开这里
Watch the thrust. We're going out of here at lightspeed.
从吊舱内部 这可能吗
From inside the hangar? Is that even possible?
我都是在做完了才问这个问题的
I never ask that question till after I've done it.
这可不是我想象中的一天
This is not how I thought this day was gonna go.
打开防护盾 后面的人坐好了
Angle the shield. Hang on back there.
没问题
No problem!
拜托 宝贝 别让我失望
Come on, baby, don't let me down.
- 什么来着 - 压缩机
- What? - Compressor.
通知第一秩序 他们要的机器人在汉・索洛手里
Inform the First Order that Han Solo has the droid they want.
它在千年隼号上
And it's aboard the Millennium Falcon.
那个机器人很快会被送到抵抗组织
The droid will soon be delivered to the Resistance...
带他们找到最后一个绝地武士
leading them to the last Jedi.
如果天行者回归
If Skywalker returns...
新一代绝地武士就会崛起
the new Jedi will rise.
最高领袖 我会负起全责
Supreme Leader, I take full responsibility...
将军
General!
我们必须要改变战略了
Our strategy must now change.
武器已经准备就绪
The weapon. It is ready.
我相信是时候派上用场了
I believe the time has come to use it.
我们将摧毁支持抵抗组织的政府
We shall destroy the government that supports the Resistance...
共和国政府
the Republic.
没有了朋友的支持 抵抗组织就会变得力量薄弱
Without their friends to protect them the Resistance will be vulnerable.
在他们找到天行者之前拦截他们
And we will stop them before they reach Skywalker.
去吧
Go.
监督好准备工作
Oversee preparations.
是 最高领袖
Yes, Supreme Leader.
有个人已经觉醒
There has been an awakening.
你感觉到了吗
Have you felt it?
是的
Yes.
还有更多的东西
There's something more.
我们要找的机器人在千年隼号上
The droid we seek is aboard the Millennium Falcon.
在你父亲手中
In the hands of your father...
汉・索洛
Han Solo.
他对我而言毫无意义
He means nothing to me.
即便是你 伦武士团的大师
Even you, master of the Knights of Ren...
也从未面临过如此挑战
have never faced such a test.
承蒙您的培养 我不会受此诱惑的
By the grace of your training, I will not be seduced.
我们拭目以待
We shall see.
- 电力超负荷了 - 我能修好
- Electrical overload. - I can fix that.
冷却剂泄露了
Coolant's leaking.
- 尝试把辅助电力转移到 - 第二燃料箱
- Try transferring auxiliary power... - ...to the secondary tank.
知道了
I got it.
丘伊 拜托
Chewie, come on!
我需要帮忙制住这个大毛怪
I need help with this giant hairy thing!
- 来了 - 别过来
Stop moving!
啊
Awww!
- 丘伊 - 他需要帮助
Chewie!
你要是伤害丘伊 就是和我作对
You hurt Chewie, you're gonna deal with me!
伤害他 他几乎杀了我六次了
Hurt him? He almost killed me six times!
这下好了
Which is fine!
如果超光速引擎爆炸
This hyperdrive blows,
我们将会变成三个不同星系的碎片
there are gonna be pieces of us in three different systems.
你做了什么
What'd you do?
我绕开了压缩机
I bypassed the compressor.
哈
Huh.
走开 圆球
Move, ball.
别那么说 你做得很棒 休息一下
Ah, don't say that. You did great. Just rest.
做得好 孩子
Good job, kid.
谢谢
Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
所以 你们是逃犯 哈
So... fugitives, huh?
第一秩序想要那张地图
The First Order wants the map.
芬恩是抵抗组织成员
Finn is with the Resistance.
我只是一个拾荒者
I'm just a scavenger.
让我们看看你拿到了什么
Let's see what you got.
- 可以吗 - 给他看吧
Go ahead.
这张地图并不完整 只是其中一块
This map's not complete. It's just a piece.
自从卢克失踪 人们就一直在找他
Ever since Luke disappeared people have been looking for him.
他为什么离开
Why did he leave?
他曾经培养了新一代绝地武士
He was training a new generation of Jedi.
有个男孩 他的徒弟 背叛了他 摧毁了一切
One boy, an apprentice, turned against him, destroyed it all.
卢克感到很自责
Luke felt responsible.
只好远离一切
He just walked away from everything.
你知道在他身上发生过什么吗
Do you know what happened to him?
有很多谣言和传说
A lot of rumors. Stories.
了解他的人猜测
People that knew him best...
他去寻找第一绝地圣殿了
think he went looking for the first Jedi temple.
绝地武士真的存在吗
The Jedi were real?
我曾经也怀疑过
I used to wonder about that myself.
我也曾认为只是一堆胡言乱语
Thought it was a bunch of mumbo-jumbo.
能够结合正义与邪恶
A magical power holding together good and evil...
黑暗和光明的神奇力量
the dark side and the light.
难以置信的是
Crazy thing is...
这是真的
it's true.
原力 绝地武士
The Force. The Jedi.
所有一切
All of it.
都是真的
It's all true.
不 你去休息
No, you rest.
你想要我帮忙 那你要听我的
You want my help? You're getting it.
去见一个老朋友 她会帮你的机器人回家
Gonna see an old friend. She'll get your droid home.
我们到了
This is our stop.
我不知道银河系中居然还有这么多绿色
I didn't know there was this much green in the whole galaxy.
嘿 索洛 我不知道我们来这干嘛
Hey, Solo, I'm not sure what we're walking into here...
你刚刚叫我索洛
Did you just call me Solo?
抱歉 汉・索洛先生
Sorry. Han. Mr. Solo.
你应该知道
You should know...
我可是抵抗组织的大人物
I'm a big deal in the Resistance.
他们真正目标是我
Which puts a real target on my back.
这里有任何阴谋者吗
Are there any conspirators here?
像是第一秩序支持者
Like, First Order sympathizers?
听着 "大人物"
Listen, Big Deal.
你有其他问题要解决
You got another problem.
女人总是能找出真相
Women always figure out the truth.
总是
Always.
你会需要这个的
You might need this.
我自己能搞定
I think I can handle myself.
我知道 这就是我为什么把它给你
I know you do. That's why I'm giving it to you.
拿着
Take it.
你知道怎么使用吗
You know how to use one of those?
知道 扣动扳机
Yeah. You pull the trigger.
实际上远远不止
Little bit more to it than that.
学无止境
You got a lot to learn.
你叫什么名字
You got a name?
蕾伊
Rey.
我一直在考虑增加一些船员 蕾伊
I been thinking about bringing on some more crew, Rey.
一个二副 能帮上忙的
A second mate. Someone to help out.
能跟上丘伊和我节奏 并且能赏识千年隼号
Someone who can keep up with Chewie and me appreciates the Falcon.
你在给我提供工作吗
Are you offering me a job?
我对你不会很好 也不会付很多钱
I wouldn't be nice to you. Doesn't pay much.
你在招募我吗
You're offering me a job.
我只是在考虑
I'm thinking about it.
怎么样
Well?
你这么说我真是受宠若惊 但我必须回家
If you were, I'd be flattered. But I have to get home.
回哪儿 贾库
Where, Jakku?
我已经离开太久了
I've already been away too long.
丘伊 好好检查一下飞船
Chewie, check out the ship as best you can.
那真遗憾 丘伊有点喜欢你呢
That's too bad. Chewie kind of likes you.
索洛 我们来这干什么
- Solo, why are we here again?
确保你的机器人能在一艘干净的船上
- To get your droid on a clean ship.
干净
Clean?
你觉得我和丘伊找到千年隼号是运气使然吗
You think it was luck that Chewie and I found the Falcon?
如果我们能在扫描仪上找到它
If we can find it on our scanners
第一秩序也离我们不远了
the First Order's not far behind.
你想把BB-8送回抵抗组织
Wanna get BB-8 to the Resistance?
玛兹・卡纳塔就是我们最好选择
Maz Kanata's our best bet.
我们能相信她吗
We can trust her, right?
放心 孩子
Relax, kid.
她开这个酒馆一千多年了
She's run this watering hole for a thousand years.
玛兹有点古怪 所以由我来跟她谈
Maz is a bit of an acquired taste, so let me do the talking.
无论你们做什么 别盯着看
And whatever you do, don't stare.
- 看什么 - 看什么
At what?
任何一切
Any of it.
汉・索洛
Han Solo!
哦 老天
Oh, boy.
嘿 玛兹
Hey, Maz.
我的男朋友呢
Where's my boyfriend?
丘伊在千年隼号上工作呢
Chewie's working on the Falcon.
我喜欢那个伍基人
I like that Wookiee.
我猜你需要一些什么东西
I assume you need something.
还挺急的
Desperately.
跟我来吧
Let's get to it.
我一会回来
I'll be back.
原谅我
Forgive me.
我又一次感受到了
I feel it again.
光明面的诱惑
The pull to the light.
最高领袖察觉到了
Supreme Leader senses it.
请再次给我展示
Show me again.
黑暗面的力量
The power of the darkness.
我绝不会让任何事情阻挡我们的道路
And I will let nothing stand in our way.
给我展示
Show me...
祖父大人
Grandfather...
我会完成
and I will finish...
你未尽的事业的
what you started.
一张能找到
A map.
天行者的地图
To Skywalker himself?
你是打算重出江湖了
You are right back in the mess.
玛兹 我需要你把这个机器人送到莱娅那
Maz, I need you to get this droid to Leia.
嗯
Hmm...
不行
No.
你已经远离这场战斗太久了
You've been running away from this fight for too long.
汉
Han.
回家吧
Go home.
莱娅不会想见我的
Leia doesn't wanna see me.
拜托 我们来这就是寻求你的帮助的
Please, we came here for your help.
什么战斗
What fight?
唯一的战斗
The only fight.
抵抗黑暗组织
Against the dark side.
古往今来 我已经见识过太多的邪恶力量
Through the ages I've seen evil take many forms.
西斯人 帝国军团
The Sith. The Empire.
现在 是第一秩序
Today, it is the First Order.
他们的阴影笼罩着整个银河系
Their shadow is spreading across the galaxy.
我们必须面对他们
We must face them.
和他们战斗
Fight them.
我们所有人
All of us.
不能和第一秩序对抗
There is no fight against the First Order.
我们不可能战胜他们
Not one we can win.
看看周围
Look around.
没机会了 我们早已被认出来了
There's no chance we haven't been recognized already.
我敢打赌第一秩序已经在来的路上了
I bet you the First Order is on their way right...
这是什么
What's this?
你干什么
What are you doing?
索洛 她在干什么
Solo, what is she doing?
我不知道 但肯定不是好事
I don't know. But it ain't good.
如果你活得够久
If you live long enough...
就能通过眼睛能看透不同的人
you see the same eyes in different people.
我看到了一个想要逃跑的人
I'm looking at the eyes of a man who wants to run.
你对我一无所知
You don't know a thing about me.
我从哪来 见过什么
Where I'm from. What I've seen.
没人比我更了解第一秩序
You don't know the First Order like I do.
他们会把我们屠杀殆尽
They'll slaughter us.
我们必须逃跑
We all need to run.
看到那两个人了吗
You see those two?
他们会把货物运往外环星域交易
They'll trade work for transportation to the Outer Rim.
在那 你可以消失
There, you can disappear.
芬恩
Finn?
跟我一起走
Come with me.
BB-8怎么办 我们还没有完成任务
What about BB-8? We're not done yet.
我们得把它送回你们基地
We have to get him back to your base.
你以为呢 他不行的
You think? He can't.
我做不到
I can't.
留着吧 孩子
Keep it, kid.
那个女孩是谁
Who's the girl?
- 什么 这是什么 - 让他先说
- What? What is it? - Let him speak first.
有人说你们可以把我带到外环星域
I was told you can get me to the Outer Rim.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
别丢下我
Don't leave without me.
你不能一走了之 我不会让你走的
You can't just go. I won't let you.
我不是你想的那样
I'm not who you think I am.
芬恩 你在说什么
Finn, what are you talking about?
我不是抵抗组织的
I'm not Resistance.
我也不是英雄
I'm not a hero.
我是一个冲锋队员
I'm a stormtrooper.
和他们一样 我从一个永远都不会知道的家庭被带走
Like all of them, I was taken from a family I'll never know.
被培养训练去杀戮
And raised to do one thing.
在我第一场战斗中 我做了一个选择
But my first battle, I made a choice.
我不想替他们杀人
I wasn't gonna kill for them.
所以我逃跑了 正好遇见了你
So I ran. Right into you.
从来没有人像你那样看我
And you looked at me like no one ever had.
我为自己感到羞耻
I was ashamed of what I was.
但是 我受够了第一秩序
But I'm done with the First Order.
我永远都不要回去
I'm never going back.
蕾伊 跟我一起走吧
Rey, come with me.
别走
Don't go.
照顾好自己
Take care of yourself.
拜托了
Please.
不要
No!
别走 回来
No! Come back!
不
No!
回来
Come back!
别走
No!
他的能量
Its energy...
- 就在我们周围 - 不要
- ...surrounds us... - No!
束缚着我们
...and binds us...
原力将成为
The Force will be...
别走
No!
回来
Come back!
安静 小丫头
Quiet, girl.
别走
No!
蕾伊
Rey?
这是你成为绝地武士的第一步
These are your first steps.
刚才那是什么
What was that?
我不该贸然进来的
I shouldn't have gone in there.
那是卢克的光剑
That lightsaber was Luke's.
在那之前属于他父亲
And his father's before him.
但是现在 它在召唤你
And now, it calls to you.
我必须要回贾库
I have to get back to Jakku.
汉跟我说了
Han told me.
孩子啊
Dear child.
我从你的眼睛里看出来了
I see your eyes.
你已经知道真相了
You already know the truth.
你在贾库等待的人
Whomever you're waiting for on Jakku...
他们再也不会回来了
they're never coming back.
但是 只有一个人例外
But... there's someone who still could.
卢克
Luke.
你苦苦追寻的归宿不在过去
The belonging you seek is not behind you...
而在未来
it is ahead.
我不是绝地武士 但我了解原力
I am no Jedi, but I know the Force.
它流转万物之间又包容万物
It moves through and surrounds every living thing.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
用心感受
Feel it.
光线
The light...
无处不在
it's always been there.
它会指引你
It will guide you.
拿上那把光剑吧
The saber. Take it.
我绝不会再碰它了
I'm never touching that thing again.
我不想牵扯进来
I don't want any part of this.
嗯
Hmm.
今天是共和国的末日
Today is the end of the Republic.
是无秩序政权终结的日子
The end of a regime that acquiesces to disorder.
在这个特别的时刻 地处遥远星系的
At this very moment, in a system far from here...
新共和国欺骗了我们
the New Republic lies to the galaxy...
秘密支持抵抗组织的
while secretly supporting the treachery...
叛徒们的谋反行为
of the loathsome Resistance.
我们将用脚下这个你们亲手建造的
This fierce machine which you have built...
毁灭性武器
upon which we stand...
将共和国和他们视为珍宝的舰队
will bring an end to the Senate!
送上西天
To their cherished fleet!
其余的星系将永远臣服于第一秩序
All remaining systems will bow to the First Order!
并且将永远铭记
And will remember this...
共和国灭亡的今天
as the last day of the Republic!
人工控制授权确认
Confirm transfer to manual control.
配置完成
Configure!
开火
Fire!
霍斯尼亚星系
*Hosnian System
新共和国
New Republic
天哪 这是什么
No. What is it?
那是新共和国
It was the Republic.
是第一秩序干的
The First Order, they've done it.
蕾伊去哪儿了
Where's Rey?
小姐 你没事吧
Mistress, are you alright?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我看见你一直在跑 你没事吧
I see you running, are you alright?
你快回去
You have to go back.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
我要走了
I'm leaving.
- BB-8 - 不
BB-8...
你不能这样
No, you can't.
你必须得回去 你太重要了
You have to go back, you're too important.
他们会帮助你的
They'll help you.
我已经保管了很久了
I've had this for ages.
我一直把它锁在这里
Kept it locked away.
你从哪儿得到的
Where'd you get that?
问得好 改天给你解释
A good question. For another time.
拿着
Take it.
找到你的朋友
Find your friend!
那群野蛮人
Those beasts.
他们打过来了
They're here.
FN-417 站在别动
FN-417, hold position.
忘了保险栓
Oh, safety.
哇哦
Wow!
长官
Sir.
有士兵报告机器人朝西逃走了
The droid was spotted heading west.
和一个女孩一起
With a girl.
快走 别让他们发现你
You have to keep going. Stay out of sight.
- 我负责牵制住他们 - 但愿他们找不到我们
I'll try to fight them off.
但愿如此
I hope so, too.
跟上 丘伊
Come on, Chewie!
蕾伊和BB-8 他们需要你
Rey and BB-8! They need you!
快去
Now! Go!
我需要一件武器
I need a weapon!
你手上不就是吗
You have one!
这个借我用用
Hey, can I try that?
我喜欢
I like this thing.
叛徒
Traitor!
- 你没事吧 "大麻烦" - 多谢
- You okay, Big Deal? - Thanks.
不许动
Don't move.
TK-338 我们已经包围了目标
TK-338, we have targets in custody.
28.6公里外敌军来袭
We have incoming at 28. 6.
前进 前进 前进
Move! Move! Move!
所有人集合 重复 所有人集合
Scramble all squads, repeat, scramble all squads!
找掩护 守住中心战场
Head to higher cover and wait for our position!
是抵抗组织
It's the Resistance.
朝着他们开火 这些暴徒没什么可怕的
Go straight at them! Don't let these dogs scare you!
- 收到 - 一起冲 波
- Copy that. - We're with you, Poe.
快走
Quick!
好耶
Whoo! Yeah!
这才是真正的飞行员
That's one hell of a pilot!
哇哦
Whoo-hoo!
我听过太多关于你的传闻
The girl I've heard so much about.
那个机器人
The droid.
在哪里
Where is it?
我们急需空中支援
Request air support.
地图
The map.
你已经看过了
You've seen it.
长官 抵抗组织派飞机过来了
Sir, Resistance fighters.
我们需要更多人手
We need more troops.
全军撤退
Pull the division out.
不用找机器人了 我们已经找到目标了
Forget the droid. We have what we need.
撤退
Pull back to tree line!
不
No!
不 不 不
No, no!
不 不
No! No!
蕾伊
Rey!
他把她带走了 你看见了吗
He took her. Did you see that?
她被带走了
He took her. She's gone.
好了 我知道了
Yeah, I know.
这边
Let's go.
天哪 汉・索洛
Goodness! Han Solo!
还记得我吗 C-3PO
It is I, C-3PO.
换了个红胳膊后你可能不认得我了
You probably don't recognize me because of the red arm.
快看这是谁 你看见
Look who it is, did you see who...
呃
Uh...
哦
Hmm.
恕我无礼 殿下 我错了 将军
Excuse me, Prin... General. Sorry.
- 走吧 BB-8 他们等着呢 - 你的胳膊真特别
Come along, BB-8, quickly.
我得赶紧换上正确的胳膊
Yes, I must get my proper arm reinstalled.
你换发型了
You changed your hair.
还是那件外套
Same jacket.
不 这件是新的
No, new jacket.
我看见他了
I saw him.
莱娅 我看见我们的儿子了
Leia, I saw our son.
他在那儿
He was here.
嘿
Hey!
波
Poe!
我的好朋友 BB-8
BB-8, my buddy.
见到你真高兴
Oh, it's so good to see you.
芬恩救了你 他在哪里
Finn saved you?
在那儿
Where is he?
波
Poe?
哦 不
Oh, no.
波・达默龙 你还活着
Poe Dameron, you're alive?
- 兄弟 你也没事 - 你去哪里了
- Buddy! So are you! - What happened to you?
我被爆炸冲击波震飞
I got thrown from the crash.
我在夜里醒来之后 既没看见你
I woke up at night. No you.
也没看见飞船 身边什么都没有
No ship. Nothing.
BB-8说是你救了他
BB-8 says that you saved him.
不 不只是我
No, no, no. It wasn't just me.
你替我完成了使命 芬恩
You completed my mission, Finn...
这是我的外套
That's my jacket.
- 没错 - 不 不
- Oh... - No, no, no.
穿着吧 很适合你
Keep it. It suits you.
芬恩 你是个好人
You're a good man, Finn.
波 我需要你的帮助
Poe, I need your help.
PZ-4CO 报告通信情况
PZ-4CO, report to communications.
奥加纳长官
General Organa...
抱歉打搅了 这是芬恩
I'm sorry to interrupt. This is Finn.
- 他想跟您谈谈 - 正好我也要和他谈谈
- He needs to talk to you. - And I need to talk to him.
你所做的一切真是勇气可嘉
That was incredibly brave what you did.
脱离第一秩序 救下这个年轻人的命
Renouncing the First Order, saving this man's life.
谢谢您 夫人 但是我的一个朋友被抓走了
Thank you, ma'am. But a friend of mine was taken prisoner.
汉跟我说了那个女孩的事情
Han told me about the girl.
对此深表遗憾
I'm sorry.
芬恩之前在基地工作过 他熟悉
Finn's familiar with the weapon that destroyed the Hosnian system.
摧毁霍斯尼亚星系的武器
He worked on the base.
你知道的一切对我们将会非常重要
We're desperate for anything you can tell us.
我的朋友就被带去那里了
That's where my friend was taken.
我得尽快赶过去
I've got to get there fast.
我乐意提供一切资源 但你得先把知道的都告诉我们
And I will do everything I can to help but first you need to tell us all you know.
你一定很痛苦
That sounds very scary.
你一定很勇敢
You must be so brave.
长官
General...
我很遗憾的通知您 从BB-8中读取的地图数据
I regret to inform you, but this map recovered from BB-8...
并不完整
is only partially complete.
更糟的是 这部分数据无法和数据库中的任何一副地图匹配
And even worse, it matches no charted system on record.
我们还是无法准确定位卢克的位置
We simply do not have enough information to locate Master Luke.
我太天真了 居然觉得能把卢克带回家
Can't believe I was so foolish to think I could find Luke and bring him home.
莱娅
Leia.
别这样
Don't do that.
怎样
Do what?
什么都别做
Anything.
她就是这样
Princesses.
我只是想帮忙
I'm trying to be helpful.
你什么时候帮过忙
When did that ever help?
除了死星那次
And don't say the Death Star.
R2 我需要你的帮助
R2, I need your help.
R2 醒醒
Wake up, R2.
BB-8
BB-8.
你这么做毫无用处
You're wasting your time.
他可能有地图数据
He might have the map.
谁都不能肯定R2的备份数据里有剩余的地图信息
It is very doubtful that R2 would have the rest of the map in his backup data.
- 我们不能把它叫醒吗 - 恐怕不能
I am afraid not.
卢克大师走了之后R2-D2就一直处在低电量模式
R2-D2 has been in low-power mode ever since Master Luke went away.
他可能永远都醒不过来了
Sadly, he may never be his old self again.
可怜的R2
Poor R2.
听我说好吗
Listen to me, will you?
我知道每次你
I know every time you...
每次你看着我 你都会想起他
Every time you look at me you're reminded of him.
你觉得我能忘掉他吗
You think I want to forget him?
我希望他回来
I want him back.
那个时候我们已经尽力了
There's nothing more we could have done.
他身上有太多外祖父的影子
There's too much Vader in him.
所以我才希望卢克能去训练他
That's why I wanted him to train with Luke.
我本不该把他送走
I just never should have sent him away.
从那时候起我就失去了他
That's when I lost him.
我也失去了你
That's when I lost you both.
我们只能用各自的方式去弥补这件事
We both had to deal with it in our own way.
我回去做我唯一擅长的事情了
I went back to the only thing I was ever any good at.
我们都一样
We both did.
我们再也找不回儿子了
We lost our son.
永远
Forever.
不
No.
是斯诺克的错
It was Snoke.
他把我们的儿子堕入黑暗
He seduced our son to the dark side.
但我们还有机会救他
But we can still save him.
我
Me.
你
You.
如果卢克都找不到他 我怎么可能做到
If Luke couldn't reach him, how could I?
卢克是绝地武士
Luke is a Jedi.
你是他的父亲
You're his father.
我相信他还是心存善念的
There is still light in him, I know it.
长官
General...
侦查兵报告敌军来袭
the reconnaissance report on the enemy base is coming.
这是哪里
Where am I?
这是我的地盘
You're my guest.
其他人呢
Where are the others?
你居然把杀手
Do you mean the murderers...
叛徒 和小偷称作你的朋友
traitors, and thieves you call friends?
你应该庆幸我不知道他们在哪儿
You'll be relieved to hear I have no idea.
你还是想置我于死地
You still want to kill me.
除非你摘下那个丑陋的面具
That happens when you're being hunted by a creature in a mask.
跟我说说那个机器人
Tell me about the droid.
他属于BB系列 由硒电池驱动 带有热扫描器
He's a BB unit with a selenium drive and a thermal hyperscan vindicator.
携带一部分的地图数据
It's carrying a section of a navigational chart.
我们有余下的部分
And we have the rest.
从帝国档案中恢复出来的 但是仍然缺最后一部分
Recovered from the archives of the Empire but we need the last piece.
你居然说服那个机器人展示给你看了
And somehow you convinced the droid to show it to you.
你
You.
一个拾荒者
A scavenger.
你该知道我可以知道任何事
You know I can take whatever I want.
你太孤单了
You're so lonely.
害怕离别
So afraid to leave.
在夜里绝望地入睡
At night, desperate to sleep.
想象一下大海
You imagine an ocean.
我看见了
I see it.
我看见了岛屿
I see the island.
和汉・索洛
And Han Solo.
你把他当做从未谋面的父亲
You feel like he's the father you never had.
他让你失望了
He would have disappointed you.
把手从我的脑袋上拿开
Get out of my head.
我知道你见过地图了
I know you've seen the map.
就在你的脑子里
It's in there.
现在你得把它展现给我
And now you'll give it to me.
别害怕 我能感受到
Don't be afraid. I feel it, too.
我不会给你展示任何东西的
I'm not giving you anything.
走着瞧
We'll see.
你
You.
你害怕
You're afraid.
永远都没法和达斯・维德一样强大
That you will never be as strong as Darth Vader.
这个拾荒者 居然能反抗你
The scavenger... resisted you?
她原力亲和力很强
She is strong with the Force.
虽然没经过训练 但是潜力无穷
Untrained, but stronger than she knows.
那个机器人呢
And the droid?
伦觉得它对我们没利用价值了
Ren believed it was no longer valuable to us.
有那个女孩就够了
That the girl was all we needed.
所以那个机器人应该已经
As a result, the droid has most likely been returned...
回到敌方的手上了
to the hands of the enemy.
他们应该已经得到地图了
They may have the map already.
我们一定要赶在抵抗组织找到天行者之前干掉他们
Then the Resistance must be destroyed before they get to Skywalker.
我们知道他们的位置
We have their location.
他们的侦查队回到伊利尼姆星系时被我们追踪了
We tracked their reconnaissance ship to the Ileenium system.
干得好
Good.
然后我们要一举消灭他们
Then we will crush them once and for all.
准备好武器
Prepare the weapon.
最高领袖 我能从那个女孩那里拿到地图数据
Supreme Leader, I can get the map from the girl.
只要您给我一些指引
I just need your guidance.
如果你说的关于这个女孩的是真的
If what you say about this girl is true...
把她带来见我
Bring her to me.
你会替我解开枷锁
You will remove these restraints...
然后打开门离开这里
and leave this cell with the door open.
你说什么
What did you say?
你会替我解开枷锁 然后打开门离开这里
You will remove these restraints and leave this cell with the door open.
我会加固这些枷锁 愚蠢的拾荒者
I'll tighten those restraints, scavenger scum.
你会替我解开枷锁 然后打开门离开这里
You will remove these restraints and leave this cell with the door open.
我会解开枷锁 然后打开门离开这里
I will remove these restraints and leave the cell with the door open.
- 你会丢下你的武器 - 我会丢下我的武器
- And you'll drop your weapon. - And I'll drop my weapon.
不
No.
警卫
Guards!
开始装载武器
Begin charging the weapon.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
武器装载中
Weapon charging.
斯纳普的侦察飞行器传来的
The scan data from Snap's reconnaissance
扫描数据证实了芬恩的报告
flight confirms Finn's report.
他们在星球内部建造了某种超光速武器
They've somehow created a hyper-lightspeed weapon built within the planet itself.
激光炮吗
A laser cannon?
我们不知道怎么形容此种规模的武器
We're not sure how to describe a weapon of this scale.
又是一颗死星
It's another Death Star.
那么简单就好了 上校
I wish that were the case, Major.
这个是当年的死星
This was the Death Star.
而这个 是弑星者基地
And this is Starkiller Base.
所以 它很大
So, it's big.
这种规模的武器的能源问题是怎么解决的
How is it possible to power a weapon of that size?
他们用的是太阳能
It uses the power of the sun.
太阳能会随着武器装载而渐渐耗尽 直到太阳消失
As the weapon is charged the sun is drained until it disappears.
夫人
Ma'am.
第一秩序现在正在重新装载他们的武器
The First Order, they're charging the weapon again now.
下次目标是我们的星系
Our system is the next target.
我的天哪
Oh, my.
没有共和国的舰队帮助 我们就完了
Without the Republic fleet, we're doomed.
好吧 我们把它炸掉怎么样
Okay. How do we blow it up?
- 总有办法能做到的 - 汉说的没错
- There's always a way to do that. - Han's right.
要成功装载规模如此大的武器
In order for that amount of power to be contained...
基地必须有某种热振荡器
that base has to have some kind of thermal oscillator.
有一个 在第四十七区域
There is one. Precinct 47.
这里
Here.
如果我们能毁掉这个振荡器
If we can destroy that oscillator...
就可能会破坏武器核心 削弱武器力量
it might destabilize the core and cripple the weapon.
- 或许能摧毁星球 - 我们会去那里
- Maybe the planet. - We'll go in there,
朝振荡器和接触到的一切发起攻击
we'll hit that oscillator with everything we've got.
他们有战舰无法穿过的保护罩
They have defensive shields that our ships cannot penetrate.
我们会破坏保护罩
We disable the shields.
孩子 你在那工作过
Kid, you worked there.
你知道些什么吗
What do you got?
我可以做到
I can do it.
我喜欢这家伙
I like this guy.
我可以关掉保护罩 但我必须在
I can disable the shields, but I have to be there.
那颗星球上
On the planet.
- 我们送你去 - 汉 你要怎么做
- We'll get you there. - Han, how?
如果我告诉你 你不会喜欢的
If I told you, you wouldn't like it.
所以 我们关掉保护罩
So we disable the shields...
拿下振荡器 然后炸掉大炮
we take out the oscillator and we blow up their big gun.
好了 走吧
All right. Let's go.
丘伊 检查一下热能器情况
Chewie, check that donal capitator.
来吧 走了
Come on. Let's go.
小心点那些东西 那可是炸弹
Finn, be careful with those. They're explosives.
还要你说啊
Now you tell me?
你知道吗 不管我们怎么吵架
You know, no matter how much we fought...
我一直都不喜欢看着你离开
I've always hated watching you leave.
这就是我做到的原因
That's why I did it.
所以你会想我的
So you'd miss me.
我真的很想你
I did miss you.
也不算很差劲吧 是吗
It wasn't all bad, was it?
嗯
Huh?
有时候还是... 挺好的
Some of it was... good.
非常好
Pretty good.
- 有些事情是不会变的 - 是啊
- Some things never change. - True.
你还是让我疯狂
You still drive me crazy.
如果你见到我们的儿子
If you see our son...
带他回家
bring him home.
长官 718号机库传感器被触发
Sir, sensors triggered in Hangar 718.
我们在搜索这个区域
We're searching the area.
她才刚开始试验自己的力量
She's just beginning to test her powers.
越晚找到她 她就越危险
The longer it takes to find her the more dangerous she becomes.
所有哨兵机器人
All sentry droids...
所有哨兵机器人 重新同步银河标准时间
all sentry droids, resynchronize to Galactic Standard Time.
时间偏移473
Offset 473.
我们要怎么进去
How are we getting in?
他们的保护罩有极小的刷新率
Their shields have a fractional refresh rate.
能阻止所有慢于光速的飞行器通过
Keeps anything traveling slower than lightspeed from getting through.
我们要以光速着陆吗
We're making our landing approach at lightspeed?
丘伊 做好准备
Chewie, get ready.
就是现在
And... Now!
我已经在提升高度了
I am pulling up!
再高一点他们就会发现我们了
I get any higher...they'll see us!
长官 718号机库没有找到她
Sir, she was not found in Hangar 718.
但所有部队都戒严了
But all troops are on alert.
把所有的机库都锁定
Put every hangar on lockdown.
她会想要偷一搜战舰逃跑的
She's going to try to steal a ship to esc...
汉・索洛
Han Solo.
翻过山脊就是导流洞了
The flooding tunnel is over that ridge.
我们从那边进去
We'll get in that way.
你在基地里的工作是什么
What was your job when you were based here?
清洁卫生
Sanitation.
你是清洁工
Sanitation?
那你怎么知道怎么关掉保护罩
Then how do you know how to disable the shields?
我不知道
I don't.
我是来这救蕾伊的
I'm just here to get Rey.
大家都指望着我们 整个银河系也指望着我们呢
People are counting on us. The galaxy is counting on us.
索洛 我们会找到方法的
Solo, we'll figure it out.
我们可以使用原力
We'll use the Force.
原力不是这样用的
That's not how the Force works.
我好冷
I'm cold.
是吗 你还冷吗
Oh, really? You're cold?
走吧
Come on.
报告
Report.
武器还有十五分钟装载成功 长官
Weapon charged in 15 minutes, sir.
嘿
Hey!
我们呆的时间越长 运气就越差
The longer we're here the less luck we're gonna have.
- 保护罩 - 我有个想法
- The shields. - I have an idea about that.
- 还记得我吗 - FN-2187
- You remember me? - FN-2187.
不再是了
Not anymore.
我叫芬恩 现在由我做主
The name's Finn and I'm in charge.
现在由我做主了 法斯玛 由我做主
I'm in charge now, Phasma. I'm in charge.
- 别激动 别激动 - 好
- Bring it down. Bring it down. - Yeah.
跟我来
Follow me.
你是否见过新的T-17S
Have you checked out the new T-17s?
我敢说T-17S有了很大的改进
The T-17s, as far as I can tell are a great improvement.
是啊 这就是他们会告诉你的
Yeah. That's what they tell you.
但是相信我 他们撑不起来
But believe me, they don't hold up.
- 他们不行吗 - 不行
- They don't? - No.
你想要我把你头上那个铁桶打下来吗
You want me to blast that bucket off your head?
关掉保护罩
Lower the shields.
你正在犯下一个滔天大错
You're making a big mistake.
照做
Do it.
索洛 如果这事有效 我们就没有多少时间去找蕾伊了
Solo, if this works, we're not gonna have a lot of time to find Rey.
别担心 孩子
Don't worry, kid.
没找到她我们是不会离开这里的
We won't leave here without her.
你不会那么蠢的相信这事会这么容易吧
You can't be so stupid as to think this will be easy.
我的部队马上就会到这片区域来杀掉你们
My troops will storm this block and kill you all.
我不同意 我们怎么处理她
I disagree. What do we do with her?
这里有垃圾倾倒槽吗
Is there a garbage chute?
垃圾压缩机呢
Trash compactor?
有的
Yeah, there is.
将军 保护罩失效了
General, their shields are down.
感谢造物主
Thank the Maker!
汉做到了 派他们进去
Han did it. Send them in.
让波全权负责进攻
Give Poe full authorization for attack.
黑队组长 速度降到亚光速
Black Leader, go to sub-lights on your call.
收到 基地
Roger, base.
红队 蓝队 听我指令
Red squad, Blue squad, take my lead.
将速度降到光速以下
Dropping out of lightspeed.
快到射程内了
Almost in range.
尽全力击中致命点
Hit the target dead center. As many runs as we can get.
接近目标
Approaching target.
敌机来袭
Fighters incoming!
即将在28.336
Coming at 28.336.
四十五 开启保护罩 开启保护罩
Forty-five! Shields up! Shields up!
派出所有舰队
Dispatch all squadrons.
好的 将军
Yes, General.
好了 把它点燃吧
All right. Let's light it up.
- 直接命中 - 但没有损坏
- Ah, direct hit. - But no damage!
我们得持续攻击
Yeah, we gotta keep hitting it.
又一轮轰炸要来了
Another bombing run.
记住 太阳消失时 他们的武器就装载成功要发射了
Remember, when the sun is gone that weapon will be ready to fire.
但只要还有一丝光线 我们就有机会
But as long as there's light, we got a chance.
波主人 敌机
Master Poe, enemy fighters!
伙计们 有很多客人来了
Guys, we got a lot of company!
我们认为他们可能会分开行动
We think they may be splitting up.
前往第四和第五战区
Heading to quadrants 4 and 5.
我们要利用机会把防爆门炸了
We'll use the charges to blow that blast door.
我去吸引火力 但我需要你的掩护
I'll go in and draw fire, but I'm gonna need cover.
你确定你要这么做吗
You sure you're up for this?
当然不确定
Hell, no.
我进去找蕾伊
I'll go in and try to find Rey.
部队肯定会跟在我们后面
The troopers will be on our tail.
我们必须做好准备
We have to be ready for that.
那边还有入口隧道可以通往...
There's an access tunnel that leads...
你这是干什么 你这样干嘛
Why are you doing that? Hmm? Why are you doing this?
我在做计划呢
I'm trying to come up with a plan.
不
No!
你还好吧
You all right?
- 还好 - 那就好
- Yeah. - Good.
你怎么样了 他伤到你了吗
What happened to you? Did he hurt you?
芬恩 你来这干什么
Finn, what are you doing here?
我们是来救你的
We came back for you.
他说什么
What'd he say?
他说这都是你的主意
That it was your idea.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是怎么跑出来的
How did you get away?
我没法解释
I can't explain it.
你也不会相信的
And you wouldn't believe it.
现在要跑了 等会再抱吧
Escape now, hug later.
我后面跟了一架敌机
I got one behind me.
- 看到了吗 - 看到了
- You see it? - Yeah. I'm on it.
- 布利偌被击中了 - 小心地面的火力
- Burillo's been hit. - Watch out for ground fire.
他们有麻烦了
They're in trouble.
我们还不能走
We can't leave.
我的朋友带着一整包炸弹呢
My friend's got a bag full of explosives.
用了吧
Let's use them.
将军 你看到了吗
General, are you seeing this?
又有两架X翼战机被击落了
Two more X-wings down.
我们舰队一半战舰都被摧毁了
That's half our fleet destroyed.
他们的武器十分钟内就要装载成功了
And their weapon will be fully charged in ten minutes.
只有奇迹发生才能救我们了
It would take a miracle to save us now.
啊
Ah.
那姑娘有一套啊
Girl knows her stuff.
隔一根柱子设置一个炸弹
We'll set the charges against every other column.
你说对了 这确实是个更好的主意
You're right. That's a better idea.
你负责上面 我负责下面
You take the top. I'll go down below.
引爆装置
Detonator.
之后在这里碰头
We'll meet back here.
去找他们
Find them.
本
Ben!
汉・索洛
Han Solo.
我等这一天已经很久了
I've been waiting for this day for a long time.
摘下那个面具 你并不需要它
Take off that mask. You don't need it.
如果我摘下面具 你觉得你会看到什么
What do you think you'll see if I do?
我儿子的脸
The face of my son.
你儿子已经死了
Your son is gone.
他跟他的父亲一样虚弱又愚蠢
He was weak and foolish like his father.
所以我毁了他
So I destroyed him.
这就是斯诺克想要你相信的
That's what Snoke wants you to believe.
但这不是真的
But it's not true.
我的儿子还活着
My son is alive.
不
No.
最高领袖是明智的
The Supreme Leader is wise.
斯诺克只是在利用你的力量
Snoke is using you for your power.
等他得到想要的东西 他就会杀了你
When he gets what he wants, he'll crush you.
你知道的
You know it's true.
太晚了
It's too late.
不 并不晚
No, it's not.
跟我离开这里 跟我回家
Leave here with me. Come home.
我们很想你
We miss you.
我很矛盾
I'm being torn apart.
我想摆脱这种痛苦
I want to be free of this pain.
我知道我必须要做什么
I know what I have to do,
但我不知道 我是否有勇气做到
but I don't know if I have the strength to do it.
你会帮我吗
Will you help me?
是的 不论何事
Yes. Anything.
不
No!
谢谢
Thank you.
不
No.
振荡器已经损坏 但还在运作中
The oscillator's been damaged but is still functional.
司令 他们的武器还有两分钟就要开火了
Admiral, their weapon will fire in two minutes.
千年隼在这边
The Falcon's this way.
我们还没玩完呢
We're not done yet.
你是个怪物
You're a monster.
现在只有我们了
It's just us now.
汉・索洛救不了你了
Han Solo can't save you.
蕾伊
Rey!
Rey.
蕾伊
Rey!
不 不要啊
Oh, no. No, no.
蕾伊
Rey.
叛徒
Traitor!
那把光剑
That lightsaber.
是属于我的
It belongs to me.
有本事来拿啊
Come get it.
星际一号被毁了
We just lost R-1.
我们已经不堪重负了
We're overwhelmed.
我们该怎么办 这样下去是不行的
What do we do? It isn't working.
黑队组长 振荡器上出现了新的空洞
Black Leader, there's a brand new hole in that oscillator.
看来我们的朋友进去了
Looks like our friends got in.
红队四号 六号 掩护我们
Red Four, Red Six, cover us.
- 我来了 - 收到
- I'm on it. - Roger.
其他人 攻击目标
Everybody else, hit the target hard.
拼尽全力
Give it everything you got.
我这边需要帮助 我需要帮助
I need some help here. I need some help!
- 来了 - 小心
- Coming in! - Watch out!
我被击中了
I'm hit!
所有小队 我要进去了
All teams, I'm going in.
过来掩护我
Pull up and cover me.
收到 黑队组长 祝你好运 波
Copy that, Black Leader. Good luck, Poe.
三十秒内武器就装载成功了
Weapon fully charged in 30 seconds.
准备开火
Prepare to fire.
你需要一名老师
You need a teacher.
我可以教你使用原力
I could show you the ways of the Force.
原力
The Force?
看看那些TIE战斗机
- All eyes on that TIE fighter.
我们正在迅速失去力量
- We're losing power rapidly!
中尉 回到你的岗位上
Lieutenant! Get back to your station!
看看周围 我们完蛋了 赫克斯都跑了
Just look! We won't survive. Even Hux is gone.
最高领袖
Supreme Leader.
燃料电池爆炸了
The fuel cells have ruptured.
星球已经开始崩塌了
The collapse of the planet has begun.
马上离开基地 跟凯洛・伦到我这来
Leave the base at once and come to me with Kylo Ren.
完成他训练的
It is time...
时间到了
to complete his training.
芬恩
Finn!
Finn.
- 所有小队 我看到他们了 - 太好了
- All teams, I got eyes on them. - Yes!
我们的任务完成了 回家吧
Our job's done here. Let's go home.
轻点 轻点 他受伤了
Easy, easy. He's hurt.
还有心跳
We've got a heartbeat.
你还好吗
How are you?
你醒了
You are awake!
R2-D2
R2-D2!
你终于回来了
You've come back.
你发现了什么
You found what?
你怎么能这样叫我
How dare you call me that!
我们必须得找到卢克主人
We have to find Master Luke.
- 怎么找到他 - 我有地图
Find Master Luke, how?
来吧 R2
Come, R2.
我们得马上告诉其他人
We must go tell the others at once!
将军
General.
打扰一下 将军
Excuse me, General.
R2-D2可能有些非常重要的好消息
R2 may contain some much-needed good news.
快告诉我吧
Tell me.
波 给我你的地图
Poe, I need your map.
好的 伙计 等等
Yeah. All right, buddy. Hold on.
地图 完整了
The map, it is complete.
卢克
Luke.
我亲爱的朋友 我真想你
Oh, my dear friend, how I've missed you.
我们还会再见面的
We'll see each other again.
我相信一定会
I believe that.
谢谢你 我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
蕾伊
Rey.
愿原力与你同在
May the Force be with you.